<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-12-04T21:54:16-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Allison Skinner Web Design and Development</title><subtitle>Allison Skinner provides custom web design, web development and web maintenance for a variety of businesses in the Athens, Georgia and Atlanta, Georgia area.
</subtitle><author><name>Allison Skinner</name></author><entry><title type="html">Here’s a 3D rotating book because I started a book club 📚</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/writing/3D-rotating-book" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Here's a 3D rotating book because I started a book club 📚" /><published>2019-10-07T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-10-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/writing/I-Started-a-book-club</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/writing/3D-rotating-book">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/img/writing/rotating-book/rotating-book.gif&quot; alt=&quot;gif of rotating 3D book. The book is STATION ELEVEN by Emily St.John Mandel&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Last month I posted on instagram, “What if we started a book club?” and to my surprise a lot of people were very interested (close friends, friends I don’t see as often and a few that I don’t know too well yet).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think a lot of us in our adult lives lose touch with reading. When we are young, reading is encouraged and enforced with compulsory literature classes, summer reading assignments and standardized testing. A lot of this early reading can feel like a chore but every so often magic strikes, and you fall into a book and the book devours you, changes you. It’s an incredible experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As adults, there is no compulsory reading and really no encouragement either. I feel like we’re pushed to be on our phones all day and compare ourselves to everyone else. We are reading all day but how much of it is valuable, how much of it holds our attention longer than seven seconds?
To put down your phone and pick up a book can feel like a revolutionary act.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s a big reason why so many wanted to join the book club. They used to have a love for reading, but somehow that love hasn’t followed them into their adult life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My hope for the book club is that people find their love for reading again. I’m personally excited to talk about books, read books that I usually wouldn’t pick out and have a reason to spend time with others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For our first month, I said I would pick the book and I’d host book club at my home. I didn’t expect picking the book would be so stressful!
My criteria for the book was the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;available in paperback&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;spooky in some way (because October)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;under 400 pages&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;page-turner but has depth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After reading many book reviews, I landed on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.indiebound.org/book/9780804172448&quot;&gt;Station Eleven&lt;/a&gt; by Emily St. John Mandel. It’s about a traveling theatre group in post-apocalyptic America.
As I’m writing this, I have not started the book yet. I’ll be starting the book tonight!
Of course, starting a book club made me also want to code a rotating 3D book because why not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you are interested in what else I’ve read, I post book reviews in my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/a.l.l.is.on/&quot;&gt;Instagram story highlights&lt;/a&gt; and I also post my reading on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/user/show/61939896-allison-skinner.&quot;&gt;GoodReads&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-the-3d-rotating-book-i-coded&quot;&gt;About the 3D Rotating Book I coded…&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I followed SuperHi’s tutorial &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.superhi.com/video/how-to-make-an-interactive-rotating-3d-cube-with-css-and-javascript&quot;&gt;How to make an interactive rotating 3d cube with CSS and Javascript&lt;/a&gt;. You can view my codepen below or &lt;a href=&quot;https://codepen.io/adskinner/pen/PoowERX&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for the full HTML, CSS and JavaScript.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe height=&quot;680&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%;&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; title=&quot;3D Rotating Book&quot; src=&quot;https://codepen.io/adskinner/embed/PoowERX?height=680&amp;amp;theme-id=light&amp;amp;default-tab=result&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; allowtransparency=&quot;true&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot;&gt;
  See the Pen &lt;a href=&quot;https://codepen.io/adskinner/pen/PoowERX&quot;&gt;3D Rotating Book&lt;/a&gt; by Allison Skinner
  (&lt;a href=&quot;https://codepen.io/adskinner&quot;&gt;@adskinner&lt;/a&gt;) on &lt;a href=&quot;https://codepen.io&quot;&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name>Allison Skinner</name></author><category term="book club" /><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/writing/rotating-book/rotating-book.gif" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Have you ever met a freelancer that failed?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/writing/Have-You-Ever-Met-A-Freelancer-that-failed" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Have you ever met a freelancer that failed?" /><published>2019-10-02T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-10-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/writing/Have-You-Ever-Met-A-Freelancer-that-failed</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/writing/Have-You-Ever-Met-A-Freelancer-that-failed">&lt;h2 id=&quot;have-you-ever-met-a-freelancer-that-failed&quot;&gt;Have you ever met a freelancer that failed?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I was asked this question by a student when I spoke to one of Lamar Dodd School of Art’s classes this Fall of 2019. [side note &lt;a href=&quot;/work/lamar-dodd-school-of-art&quot;&gt;Lamar Dodd School of Art&lt;/a&gt; is one of my clients!] We were discussing running a business as an artist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the student asked this question, I was struck by the word “failed”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because to “fail” means you tried, really hard. And honestly, when I see a freelancer or any business owner try very hard…they don’t fail.
When I answered the student, I rephrased the question for my answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I haven’t met freelancers that “failed” but I have met freelancers that never made it, I said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Freelancers that never make their work their whole &lt;em&gt;thing&lt;/em&gt;. Freelancer that phrase their work as something they do “on the side”, “sometimes”, “a little bit”. Freelancers that never leave their full-time job*. Freelancers that say “I’m not a professional at this or anything”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are the ones that do not make it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I wanted to tell you what I told the student.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;if-you-are-going-to-be-a-freelancer-aka-become-a-business-owner-you-need-to-make-your-business-your-whole-identity&quot;&gt;If you are going to be a freelancer (aka become a business owner), you need to make your business your &lt;em&gt;whole&lt;/em&gt; identity.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What you do should be on every social media profile of yours, it should be the first way you describe yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe you work at a coffee shop full-time to pay the bills (what I did all through college). But you aren’t a barista, you are a photographer (or web developer, or videographer, or writer).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When someone asks you what you do, say “I’m a photographer” not “I do photography on the side sometimes”. Even if you only have one photography client a month. Who cares.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, if you want to be a business owner you should put all your eggs in that basket, aka make it a full-time commitment, as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(I will say that freelancing isn’t for everyone and some people thrive working full-time for a company. I support that 100%!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was thrust into full-time freelancing after I got fired from my first agency job. I got fired because I published my freelance portfolio website. I just wanted to make a few thousand dollars to pay off a new (to me, very used to the world) car. I did not want to quit my job. I did not want to freelance full-time. That’s because I didn’t think I would make it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting fired was the best thing that happened to me. It forced me to commit 110% to freelancing. I had no savings, I had no clients, but I had 24 hours a day to try. &lt;em&gt;To try very hard&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;also-money&quot;&gt;Also, money.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you are a freelancer, money will be something you talk about every day. Money will be something that doesn’t come every two weeks. My advice is to..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get over any weirdness you have about money.&lt;/strong&gt; Know what you have, know what you need to survive or thrive, know how to give a fair quote to clients. And when I say fair, I mean fair to you. Fair enough that you can make a living! Read more about my money thoughts @ &lt;a href=&quot;/writing/How-File-Taxes-as-a-Freelancer&quot;&gt;How to File your Taxes as a Freelancer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Save money. Obsessively.&lt;/strong&gt; Literally nothing will feel better than knowing that you could have no work and no income for six full months and you’ll be fine. Like paying your bills and meeting your friends for dinner kind of fine. Actually the only thing that will feel better than that will be having enough for a whole year (my current goal). In the three years since I started my business, I’ve let my consumerism fade away. I don’t crave many things. I can attribute that to the fact that many affordable things make me very happy (library books, grocery shopping, exercising). Another benefit to saving money is that you can be more picky about the work you choose. If a project sounds stressful with a not-so-nice client — skip it! You can afford to. Money is not what determines happiness, but it can give you some peace of mind and a little freedom.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, no, I don’t think anyone is destined to fail at freelancing. I do think some will give up on it before they really, really try to make it work. And I want you to know, that one, I believe in anyone who wants to do this — I don’t care if you have no clients, savings or experience. And, two, I’m here for any questions or advice on how to run a business independently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*There are some freelancers that ❤ their full-time job and love the freelancing they do on the side and I totally respect that. However I do see a lot of people that never quit their full-time job because of fear and self-doubt. That’s who I’m talking to here!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Allison Skinner</name></author><category term="freelancing" /><summary type="html">Have you ever met a freelancer that failed?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/writing/freelance-fail/freelance-fail.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How To: overlapping sections on scroll</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/writing/overlapping-sections" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How To: overlapping sections on scroll" /><published>2019-09-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-09-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/writing/overlapping-sections</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/writing/overlapping-sections">&lt;p&gt;Hello 👋!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/img/writing/overlap-scroll/overlap-scroll.gif&quot; alt=&quot;gif of me scrolling through the mobile version of my website. Each section overlaps the other on scroll&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I wanted to share how you can create on-scroll overlapping sections with some basic CSS.
When building my portfolio website, I wanted the homepage to have a special on-scroll feature that felt unique but not overwhelming.
I found what I was looking for on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.superhi.com/video/parallax-overlapping-sections-using-sticky-positioning&quot;&gt;SuperHi’s tutorial: “Parallax overlapping sections using sticky positioning”&lt;/a&gt;. It was easy, elegant – just what I was looking for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also view the code I used to do this on codepen 👇&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe height=&quot;500&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%;&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; title=&quot;Overlapping sections with position sticky&quot; src=&quot;https://codepen.io/adskinner/embed/NWKeLZW?height=265&amp;amp;theme-id=light&amp;amp;default-tab=result&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; allowtransparency=&quot;true&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot;&gt;
  See the Pen &lt;a href=&quot;https://codepen.io/adskinner/pen/NWKeLZW&quot;&gt;Overlapping sections with position sticky&lt;/a&gt; by Allison Skinner
  (&lt;a href=&quot;https://codepen.io/adskinner&quot;&gt;@adskinner&lt;/a&gt;) on &lt;a href=&quot;https://codepen.io&quot;&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Organize your content into sections.&lt;/strong&gt; In my codepen example, I organized my content sections using the &amp;lt;section&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/section&amp;gt;html tag.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Add the following CSS to each section.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;section&lt;/strong&gt; {&lt;br /&gt;
  position: sticky;&lt;br /&gt;
  position: -webkit-sticky;&lt;br /&gt;
  top: 0;&lt;br /&gt;
}&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Allison Skinner</name></author><summary type="html">Hello 👋!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Allison’s SEO Basics Series: Pt 2. On-page SEO Optimization</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/writing/Allison-SEO-Basics-Pt-2-On-Page-SEO-Optimization" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Allison’s SEO Basics Series: Pt 2. On-page SEO Optimization" /><published>2019-09-23T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-09-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/writing/Allison-SEO-Basics-Pt-2-On-Page-SEO-Optimization</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/writing/Allison-SEO-Basics-Pt-2-On-Page-SEO-Optimization">&lt;h2 id=&quot;welcome-to-part-️of-my-four-part-seo-series&quot;&gt;Welcome to Part ✌️of my four part SEO Series.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;'/writing/Allison-SE0-Basics-Series-1'&quot;&gt;How hard will SEO be for your business?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On-page SEO optimization (you’re here!)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How Content can drive SEO results [coming soon!]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEO Tools and How to use them [coming soon!]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On-page SEO optimization includes a variety improvements you can make to the pages of your website that can improve your search rankings. These improvements are free and fairly easy to do, and will improve your organic search rankings.
Many on-page optimizations will be a part of the basic structure of your website, which means that the optimizations will have lasting effects with minimal effort.
Or, the on-page optimizations will be incorporated into the basic workflow of managing your website. If you start adding re-sized, optimized images with descriptive alt texts, it’ll become habit for you. Good SEO comes from good habits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;choosing-your-keywords&quot;&gt;Choosing your Keywords&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-a-keyword&quot;&gt;What is a keyword?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A “keyword” is simply the phrase you type into a search engine (like Google) to search the internet.
For example, if you are looking for carpet cleaning company in Athens, Georgia you’ll likely search something along the lines of “carpet cleaners athens, ga”.
In this example, “carpet cleaners athens, ga” is the keyword.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/img/writing/seo2/keyword.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Person typing into google search &amp;quot;Whatever I type in here is a keyword!!!&amp;quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you want to optimize your website for certain keywords, you first need to determine which keywords will be the best fit and drive the best results for your business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start by asking yourself what people will likely search for when they are looking of your business’s goods or services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my business, I provide custom web design and web development services for clients nationwide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A prospective client is most likely to search “web design”, “web development”, “web designer”, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I mostly serve the Athens, Georgia area, my prospective clients are likely going to search “web design athens, ga” or “web development athens, ga”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;keyword-tools&quot;&gt;Keyword Tools&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See what keywords your competition ranks for.  I like to use &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.spyfu.com/&quot;&gt;SpyFu&lt;/a&gt; for this. You can enter the domain of your competitor’s website and see all of the keywords they rank for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See what keywords you already rank for.  I like to use &lt;a href=&quot;https://search.google.com/search-console/about&quot;&gt;Google Search Console&lt;/a&gt;. After you connect your domain to a google search console account, you can track what people are searching to find your website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See how likely you’ll rank for a kewyord. I liek to use &lt;a href=&quot;https://moz.com/explorer&quot;&gt;Moz’s keyword explorer&lt;/a&gt;. Moz will rank the strength of each keyword and give you an assessment of how likely you’ll be able to rank high for the keyword.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;structuring-copy&quot;&gt;Structuring Copy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The “copy” on your website is the words on your website. Headings, subheadings, body copy, image captions, menu links, etc.
All website copy is structured through some basic HTML tags.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/img/writing/seo2/h1-h6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;example of h1-h6 copy structure. With h1 title being largest and h6 being the smallest&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;h1&quot;&gt;h1&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;H1 should be the main page title for your web page. For example the &amp;lt;h1&amp;gt; tag for my About page is “About Allison Skinner Web Design &amp;amp; Development”.
There should only be one &amp;lt;h1&amp;gt; title and it should clearly convey what your web page is about. If your web page has a desired keyword, it’s also beneficial to have it included in your H1 title.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;h2-h3-h4-h5-h6&quot;&gt;h2, h3, h4, h5, h6&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The remaining h tags serve as subheadings below your H1 page title.
When you are structuring your copy, you should follow the proper order of the H tags for your subheadings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/img/writing/seo2/correct-copy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;example of copy structure that follows correct linear path from h1 to h2 to h3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the above example the order of htags goes from H1 → H2 → H3. This is good for accessibility and improving search engine results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/img/writing/seo2/incorrect-copy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;example of copy structure that follows a incorrect, non-linear copy structure from h1 to h3 to h2 to h4 to h2 &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the above incorrect example the order of htags goes from H1 → H3 → H2 → H4 → H2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Correct copy structure is also important for accessibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-is-accessiblity&quot;&gt;What is accessiblity?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To have an “accessible” website means that people with disabilities, especially those with vision impairment or motor impairment, can successfully navigate and understand your website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people with disabilities use a screen reader to navigate websites. Screen readers depend on correct H tag copy structures to know the order of importance for copy on the website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check your site’s accessibility &lt;a href=&quot;https://achecker.ca/checker/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;url-path-structure&quot;&gt;URL Path Structure&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your URL path structure is the url patterns your web pages follow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/img/writing/seo2/site-url.png&quot; alt=&quot;image of browser toolbar with the url allisondskinner.com/work/the-lamar-dodd-school-of-art entered&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, on my website, my portfolio examples follow a linear url pattern.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/img/writing/seo2/correct-path.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image of how url path structure is broken down from main site url, archive title, post title&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here would be an example of a NON linear URL pattern.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/img/writing/seo2/incorrect-path.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image of how url path structure can become non-linear by not having consistent path patterns.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to create non-linear URLs on your website. This usually occurs if you duplicates pages or posts. When you duplicate a page or a post, it’ll copy the url and add a “-2” to the end or include “copy” in the url.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For example:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;allisondskinner.com/about-2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;^ This would happen if I duplicated my “About” page to start my “Process” page but never changed the url to “/process” instead of “/about-2”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Google crawls and indexes your website, it will create a site map of all the links on your website. If you site map follows a clear, linear path pattern and the urls correctly describe the purpose of the page, Google will be able to correctly index and rank the content on your site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-to-create-a-correct-url-path-structures-on-your-website&quot;&gt;How to create a correct URL path structures on your website.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, create a site map of your website and determine the URL path patterns you desire&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/img/writing/seo2/site-tree.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;a visual aid of my site map. Site map is included in blog copy below.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Main Page&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;allisondskinner.com [main site url]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top Level pages&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Path pattern: [main site url]/[page title]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;allisondskinner.com/about&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;allisondskinner.com/process&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;allisondskinner.com/services&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;allisondskinner.com/contact&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Archive Level pages&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Path pattern: [main site url]/[archive title]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;allisondskinner.com/work&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;allisondskinner.com/writing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Archive sub level pages&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Path pattern: [main site url / archive title / post title ]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;allisondskinner.com/work/[portfolio post title]&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;allisondskinner.com/work/[writing post title]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then make sure that all of the pages on your website follow the correct path structure.
If they do not, change the URL path structure and create a redirect from your old url to your new url.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Depending on the platform you are using (wordpress, drupal, shopify, squarespace, wix, etc.) the steps will be different for this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every online platform makes it possible for you to augment your URL and create redirects. Simply google search how to do it, explore your website platform’s knowledge base, or open a support ticket with your website platform. (Also an option is to hire me, I’ve done this for many clients!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;meta-information&quot;&gt;Meta Information&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every web page or post on the internet has “meta” information. This information is usually located in the &amp;lt;head&amp;gt; of your &amp;lt;html&amp;gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/img/writing/seo2/meta.png&quot; alt=&quot;screenshot of meta information in the html head of my website. Includes site title and description&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you see a search engine result, it’s pulling the meta title and meta description. For example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/img/writing/seo2/google-result.png&quot; alt=&quot;screenshot of how my meta information, site title and description, show up in google search result&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default, your meta title will be your page or post title and your meta description will be the first ~160 words of copy found beneath your page or post title.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your meta title and your meta description should accurately describe the purpose of your web page, include your desired keyword and include your region if you are a local business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the default meta title and meta description do not accurately describe the purpose of your web page or do not include the keywords you wish to rank for, you can manually change the meta title and meta description of your web page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can do this in the HTML of your web page, but most of us don’t have raw HTML sites. Most of us use a platform like wordpress, drupal, shopify, squarepace, wix, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some platforms allow you to edit your meta title and meta description and will provide you a preview of how your web page will look in Google search results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On other platforms, you will need to download a plugin to make these changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;images&quot;&gt;Images&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/img/writing/seo2/image-alt.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;This will be a bit meta, but this is an image of an image with the alt tag marked. The image is of my pug named cooper sitting on a decorative dog pillow.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Images, many times, can be the most visually intriguing part of a website.
However, images offer the least amount of information to search engines.
When you consider the saying “a picture is worth a thousand words”, for SEO the thousand words is actually more valuable than the picture.
Whenever you add an image to your website, you need to add a detailed description of the image to the image’s ALT Tag.
Every website platform offer’s an easy way to do this.
A descriptive ALT tag allows search engines to better index your images and it also provides context to visually impaired users that visit your website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;page-load-time-ie-page-performance&quot;&gt;Page load time, i.e page performance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s annoying when you’re quickly trying to visit a website, but it takes forever to load. Google finds it annoying too, and if your website loads slow, Google will lower your ranking because of it.
You can test the speed of your website on &lt;a href=&quot;https://gtmetrix.com&quot;&gt;GT Metrix&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/img/writing/seo2/gtmetrix.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of GT Metrix score for GT Metrix site&quot; /&gt;
GT Metrix will scan your web page and provide your page load time and overall page speed score.
Your speed score is broken down into ways you can improve the site load time of your website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-few-basic-ways-you-can-dramatically-improve-page-performance-include&quot;&gt;A few basic ways you can dramatically improve page performance include:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Optimizing images.&lt;/strong&gt;
 When you take a picture on your smart phone or camera, the original image file will be a large, high-resolution image. In many cases, the image file size will be larger than you need it to be. For example, a 5000px wide image is not necessary on a website because desktop screens don’t even stretch to 5000px wide.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Before adding images to your website, you should resize your images to be at least less than 500k in file size (Even better 250k). You can do this using the “Preview” application on Macs or using other photo editing software, like Photoshop. You can also adjust the quality of your image in Photoshop to further decrease image sizes. Most platforms (Wordpress, Squarespace, Shopify, etc.) allow you edit images directly on your website.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leveraging browser cache.&lt;/strong&gt;
 Your GT Metrix page speed score may fail you for “Leveraging browser cache”. This is a simple fix that can lead to big page speed improvements.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.collectiveray.com/wp/tips/leverage-browser-caching-wordpress&quot;&gt;Here’s an article&lt;/a&gt; that offers a variety of ways you can leverage browser cache.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Less is more”.&lt;/strong&gt;
 The less “stuff” you have weighing your website down, the faster your website will load. This means you should only have what’s vital on your website.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;The includes plugins, scripts, stylesheets, fonts, images, etc. on your website. The less of that stuff, the faster your website will load.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Many websites do need a lot of that “stuff” to run a more complex website, for instance an online shop. In that case, you’ll need to be smart about how your content loads. For example, placing any extra javascript files in the footer of your website so they don’t halt the initial load of your web page. Another example would be merging and minifying stylesheets and scripts.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keep everything updated.&lt;/strong&gt;
 Most likely your website runs on a CMS platform such as Wordpress or Drupal. These CMS platforms regularly have updates that will improve security and performance for your website. Third party plugins also require frequent updates. It’s important to stay on top of updating your cms system, themes and plugins because it will ensure that everything is running at it’s best efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;in-conclusion&quot;&gt;In conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These fairly basic steps will set your site up for SEO success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On-page SEO optimization provides a structure for your website that allows search engines, such as Google, to properly index your website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On-page SEO optimization is FREE to do and can have lasting effects for your website’s rankings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&quot;/writing/Allison-SE0-Basics-Series-1&quot;&gt;first part of my SEO series&lt;/a&gt;, I discussed whether SEO will be hard or easy for your website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you fall into the camp of “easy” (physical location, little competition, universally understood product or service, have been around for years) then following basic on-page SEO optimization will likely drive your business to the top of google rankings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you fall into the camp of “hard” (online only business, lots of competition, new type of product or service, haven’t been around for long) then on-page SEO optimization is an important start. The next step will be creating content that will bring site traffic and improve search rankings.
That will be covered in Part 3 of my SEO Basics series, “How Content Can Drive SEO Results” [COMING SOON!].&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Allison Skinner</name></author><category term="SEO" /><summary type="html">Welcome to Part ✌️of my four part SEO Series.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/writing/seo2/seo2-cover.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Allison’s SEO Basics Series: Pt 1. How hard will SEO be for your business?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/writing/Allison-SE0-Basics-Series-1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Allison’s SEO Basics Series: Pt 1. How hard will SEO be for your business?" /><published>2019-09-16T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-09-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/writing/Allison-SE0-Basics-Series-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/writing/Allison-SE0-Basics-Series-1">&lt;h2 id=&quot;welcome-to-part-one-of-my-seo-basics-series&quot;&gt;Welcome to Part One of my SEO Basics series!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought this would be one post, but then it got very long — so I’ve broken it up into four parts&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How Hard will SEO be for your business?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/writing/Allison-SEO-Basics-Pt-2-On-Page-SEO-Optimization&quot;&gt;On-Page SEO Optimization tips&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How Content can drive SEO results&lt;/strong&gt; [coming soon!]&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEO Tools and How to use them&lt;/strong&gt; [coming soon!]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should start by saying that I do not consider myself an SEO expert. There are agencies and professionals that do SEO full-time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I do consider myself SEO &lt;em&gt;smart&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I focus on organic (aka FREE) search growth for my clients. I do this through on-page SEO optimization. I then equip my clients with advice and tools to continue their SEO growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the first conversations I have with my clients is how &lt;em&gt;hard&lt;/em&gt; SEO is going to be for their business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some businesses can put in minimal effort and they will rank at the top of the first page in Google. Other businesses have to put in consistent, valuable effort to be able to rank as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What determines the haves and have nots? That’s what I’ll be breaking down today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;seo-will-come-easier-for-businesses-that&quot;&gt;SEO will come &lt;em&gt;easier&lt;/em&gt; for businesses that…&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;have-a-local-physical-location-with-a-google-business-profile&quot;&gt;Have a local, physical location (with a Google Business profile)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you are a local business with a physical location you will organically have an easier time getting to the first page of google search results. This is because you have a regional audience so you will show up for regional keyword searches.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For example, let’s say you are a Veterinarian with a vet clinic in Athens, Georgia. If someone searches “vet athens, ga” your only competition in the search results is other vet clinics in Athens, Georgia. Your competition is not every vet clinic in the USA.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you do have a physical location, you should have a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/business/&quot;&gt;Google Business&lt;/a&gt; profile. This means your business will show up in Google maps and that Google can better index your website and location. If someone searches for you on Google, your profile is what will show up on the right-hand side.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you want a funny read, my father, co-founder of &lt;a href=&quot;https://athenticbrewing.com&quot;&gt;Athentic Brewing Company&lt;/a&gt;, wrote a blog post about the baffling (to him) process of getting their location verified on Google.
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;do-not-have-a-lot-of-competition-with-similar-businesses&quot;&gt;Do not have a lot of competition with similar businesses&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Whenever someone searches on Google for your type of service or product, you are in competition with others that sell similar services or products.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For example, let’s say you’re still a veterinarian with a vet clinic in Athens, Ga. Your success in search results will depend on how many other vet clinics there are in Athens, Ga. If there are only ~5 vet clinics in Athens, GA then you will have a good chance of appearing high in the search results. However, if there’s ~50 vet clinics in Athens, GA then you will have a harder time getting to the top of search results because you’ll be competing with all 50 other vet clinics.
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;provide-a-service-or-sell-a-product-that-is-universally-knownunderstood&quot;&gt;Provide a service or sell a product that is universally known/understood&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Having a universally known/understood product or service means that people know how to search for your product or service on Google.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keeping with the vet example, anyone who is a pet owner knows what a veterinarian is and knows the basic services a veterinarian can provide. That means people know what to search for when they looking for a veterinarian.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;However, if your business is a totally new concept that people need to learn about before understanding it, then google search will be more difficult. If someone doesn’t know it exists they won’t search for it!
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;have-been-in-business-and-have-had-a-website-for-their-business-for-years&quot;&gt;Have been in business and have had a website for their business for years.&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If your business has been open for 10 years and you’ve had a website for your business for 10 years, Google will recognize that and give your business more validity than a new business.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;seo-will-be-tougher-for-businesses-that&quot;&gt;SEO will be &lt;em&gt;tougher&lt;/em&gt; for businesses that…&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;have-no-localphysical-location-and-sellprovide-services-nationwide&quot;&gt;Have no local/physical location and sell/provide services nationwide&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Having an online shop with no physical location or regional focus means you can sell your products nationwide but it also means that you are in competition with every other similar online shop nationwide.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Let’s say that you make beautiful pillows that you sell online. If someone searches “decorative pillows” on google search, your small, successful business may never get to the first page of google search results. That’s because the big companies like Target, Walmart, Amazon, Wayfair, etc. will always rank above you.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In these cases, I suggest that you focus on long tail keywords or niche keywords for better rankings. For example, your pillow website might have a better chance ranking for “indigo dyed pillows” or “organic linen pillows”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I also recommend that small online shops focus on social media to grow their brand and followers. You’re more likely to get someone to visit your pillow website from your instagram account than someone finding your pillow website on page 7 of google search results for “decorative pillows”.
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;have-a-lot-of-similar-competition&quot;&gt;Have a lot of similar competition&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The more saturated a market is, the more difficult it is to rank on google search results. Going back to my veterinarian example…if there are only 5 vet clinics in Athens, GA, your vet clinic is likely to rank well, but if there are 50 vet clinics in Athens, GA, you will have to put in more effort to rank high.
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;have-services--andor-products-that-are-not-universally-knownunderstood&quot;&gt;Have services  and/or products that are not universally known/understood&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you are a start-up with a revolutionary idea — that’s amazing! However, people won’t know to search for your product or service if they don’t know it exists. Therefore high google search rankings won’t come organically.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;These types of businesses need to “disrupt” the market. They need to change the status quo of purchasing decisions through smart marketing campaigns. For example, before &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blueapron.com/&quot;&gt;Blue Apron&lt;/a&gt; disrupted grocery shopping, no one was searching for “meal delivery subscriptions”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;These types of businesses need to focus on social media and advertising before they’ll see the SEO results they desire.
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;are-a-new-business&quot;&gt;are a NEW business&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you are opening a brand-spanking new business, congratulations! I love and support entrepreneurialism. However, be prepared to be patient for Google to show you the same kind of love in search rankings.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This is because, first off, it will take time for Google to fully index your website. In my experience, this usually take 2 weeks and sometimes up to a month.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Then, you need to wait for Google to recognize you as the best search result. It can be tough to beat out businesses that have been around longer than you. However, if you put in consistent, valuable effort you’ll see the benefits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Now you likely have an idea of whether it’ll be hard or easy to have SEO success for your business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For those that will have an easier time with SEO&lt;/strong&gt;, good for you! To secure your high rankings, continue reading parts 2, 3 &amp;amp; 4 of my SEO Basics series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For those that will have a harder time with SEO&lt;/strong&gt;, let’s get to work! The first step will be to improve your organic search engine rankings. Continue with parts 2, 3 &amp;amp; 4 of my SEO Basics series.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Allison Skinner</name></author><category term="SEO" /><summary type="html">Welcome to Part One of my SEO Basics series! I thought this would be one post, but then it got very long — so I’ve broken it up into four parts</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/writing/seo1/seocover-1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How I built my custom ‘Thank You’ redirection page</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/writing/19-contact-form" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How I built my custom 'Thank You' redirection page" /><published>2019-08-16T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-08-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/writing/19-contact-form</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/writing/19-contact-form">&lt;iframe height=&quot;605&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%;&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; title=&quot;particles.js demo&quot; src=&quot;//codepen.io/adskinner/embed/drjvZY/?height=605&amp;amp;theme-id=light&amp;amp;default-tab=result&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; allowtransparency=&quot;true&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot;&gt;
  See the Pen &lt;a href=&quot;https://codepen.io/adskinner/pen/drjvZY/&quot;&gt;particles.js demo&lt;/a&gt; by Allison Skinner
  (&lt;a href=&quot;https://codepen.io/adskinner&quot;&gt;@adskinner&lt;/a&gt;) on &lt;a href=&quot;https://codepen.io&quot;&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-redirection-to-a-thank-you-page&quot;&gt;Why Redirection to a Thank You page?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted anyone that fills out my contact form get redirected to a “thank you” page for a few reasons…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They know the form submission successfully sent.&lt;/strong&gt; When you fill out a form online and click submit, it’s nice to have confirmation that it has been received. Otherwise you are left wondering if it got sent at all!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Provide a note from myself about next steps.&lt;/strong&gt; On my thank you page I let my leads know that I’ll respond to them in 1-3 business days. This sets the expectation that I will be getting back to them, but it likely won’t happen within the next few minutes or over the weekend.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It’s always nice to say thank you!&lt;/strong&gt; My mom always made me write thank you notes growing up. As a teenager, it felt like a chore. Now I think it’s an opportunity! I wish I could send written thank you notes to everyone that contacted me, but I can at least dedicate a moment to thanking them on my website. That’s because I am very thankful! The majority of my client relationships start with a contact form submission.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-did-i-set-up-the-redirection&quot;&gt;How did I set up the Redirection?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I built my site on Jekyll, a static site generator, I had to use a third party to handle my contact form submissions. I chose &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.formbucket.com/&quot;&gt;Form Bucket&lt;/a&gt; because it was customizable at a developer level, dependable and had spam protection.
In the form settings, there is an option for a ‘custom redirect’, I provided the thank you page URL in this field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-did-i-do-the-animation&quot;&gt;How did I do the animation?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The animated stars is achieved through particles.js, a javascript library for animating “particles” (or other objects like stars!).
I used particles.js on the Athentic Brewing Company’s homepage as well. The effect is like bubbles coming up in a glass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Particles.js is very easy to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;First, I use the handy simulator on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://vincentgarreau.com/particles.js/&quot;&gt;particles.js&lt;/a&gt; website to decide the type of animation I want.
You can decide shape, direction, speed, density, color, etc. Play around and decide what you’d like.
&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/img/writing/19-3-19/screenshot1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Particles.js simulator&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then click the “codepen” button in the top right corner. This will create a code pen with your custom parameters.
&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/img/writing/19-3-19/screenshot2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;codepen button on particle.js simulator&quot; /&gt;
You can adjust your parameters further if you’d like.
&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/img/writing/19-3-19/screenshot4.png&quot; alt=&quot;screenshot of codepen page&quot; /&gt;
For example, &lt;strong&gt;if you’d like there to be more than one color for the animated objects, you can create an array like so..&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&quot;color&quot;: {
  &quot;value&quot;: [&quot;#5D47BA&quot;,&quot;#FFDBFF&quot;,&quot;#FB5435&quot;,&quot;#E00A30&quot;,&quot;#04CEF9&quot;]
  },&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The codepen will have you set up for success. If you are going to add the particles.js animation to your site you should add the “custom” js (what’s in the righthand side) as seperate JS file &lt;em&gt;below&lt;/em&gt; your universal particles.min.js file, that way it can pick up your custom parameters.
This is how it looks on my site…
&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/img/writing/19-3-19/screenshot3.png&quot; alt=&quot;screenshot of code on my site for particles.js simulator&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Final Result!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;iframe height=&quot;605&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%;&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; title=&quot;particles.js demo&quot; src=&quot;//codepen.io/adskinner/embed/drjvZY/?height=605&amp;amp;theme-id=light&amp;amp;default-tab=result&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; allowtransparency=&quot;true&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot;&gt;
  See the Pen &lt;a href=&quot;https://codepen.io/adskinner/pen/drjvZY/&quot;&gt;particles.js demo&lt;/a&gt; by Allison Skinner
  (&lt;a href=&quot;https://codepen.io/adskinner&quot;&gt;@adskinner&lt;/a&gt;) on &lt;a href=&quot;https://codepen.io&quot;&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name>Allison Skinner</name></author><category term="particles.js" /><category term="contact form" /><summary type="html">See the Pen particles.js demo by Allison Skinner (@adskinner) on CodePen. Why Redirection to a Thank You page? I wanted anyone that fills out my contact form get redirected to a “thank you” page for a few reasons… They know the form submission successfully sent. When you fill out a form online and click submit, it’s nice to have confirmation that it has been received. Otherwise you are left wondering if it got sent at all! Provide a note from myself about next steps. On my thank you page I let my leads know that I’ll respond to them in 1-3 business days. This sets the expectation that I will be getting back to them, but it likely won’t happen within the next few minutes or over the weekend. It’s always nice to say thank you! My mom always made me write thank you notes growing up. As a teenager, it felt like a chore. Now I think it’s an opportunity! I wish I could send written thank you notes to everyone that contacted me, but I can at least dedicate a moment to thanking them on my website. That’s because I am very thankful! The majority of my client relationships start with a contact form submission.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/writing/19-3-19/contact-redirect-wide.gif" /></entry><entry><title type="html">2019: Mid-year Review</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/writing/midyear-review-19" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2019: Mid-year Review" /><published>2019-07-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-07-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/writing/midyear-review-19</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/writing/midyear-review-19">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We’re already halfway through 2019, crazy right?
I’m saying that’s “crazy” when really 2019 has been very…chill. And I like it. I like it a LOT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was overbooked and stressed the first half of 2018. I had been overbooked for over 18 months at that point and I was burnt out. By June 2018, I didn’t want to even look at a website, let alone build one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also gained weight, lost touch with some of my friends and overall lost my identity outside of work.
I recovered in the second half of 2018 by taking some time off work and making exercise a big part of my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ended 2018 with #goodvibes and I have carried them into 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-im-really-proud-of-halfway-through-2019&quot;&gt;What I’m really proud of halfway through 2019:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’ve stayed steadily booked but not overbooked&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’ve saved money&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’m physically fit for the first time in my life (and down 25 lbs!)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’ve read a lot of books&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I launched my new portfolio site (you’re looking at her right now!!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-id-like-to-improve-in-the-second-half-of-2019&quot;&gt;What I’d like to improve in the second half of 2019&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Push my site designs. I know the default “easy” website that a lot of my clients want, but I want to reach for the incredible website that my clients wouldn’t be able to imagine.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improve workflow/programming knowledge.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Have a nice-looking yard. It’s the first time I’ve ever wanted this? I want curb appeal??&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;january&quot;&gt;January&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/img/portfolio/demmie-hicks/dh-home.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Demmie Hicks&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;launched-demmie-hicks-at-demmiehickscom&quot;&gt;Launched Demmie Hicks at &lt;a href=&quot;http://demmiehicks.com/&quot;&gt;demmiehicks.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Demmie Hicks is a consultant for executive leaders. She wanted a professional, welcoming and unique website that made her stand out from other corporate websites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What I Read:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/img/writing/2019-midyear/great-believers.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Great Believers cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.avidbookshop.com/book/9780735223523&quot;&gt;The Great Believers&lt;/a&gt; by Rebecca Makkai&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;feburary&quot;&gt;Feburary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On Feburary 1, I turned 26!&lt;/strong&gt;
Wooo into the second half of my twenties now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Took a trip to Asheville with my family.&lt;/strong&gt;
The first two nights, Jeff and I stayed with my family and visited local breweries and restaurants.
The second two nights, Jeff and I stayed at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.omnihotels.com/hotels/asheville-grove-park?&amp;amp;gclid=Cj0KCQjw1MXpBRDjARIsAHtdN-0kfIxPlGvZ2o4k6UBlJOL4gx0sOuV2ovIZjiveG10dmu0RiISfy4YaAglNEALw_wcB&amp;amp;gclsrc=aw.ds&quot;&gt;Grove Park Inn&lt;/a&gt;. It was beautiful and so peaceful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What I Read:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/img/writing/2019-midyear/vitamin.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Goodbye Vitamin cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.avidbookshop.com/book/9781250182555&quot;&gt;Goodbye Vitamin&lt;/a&gt; by Rachel Konig&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/img/writing/2019-midyear/wolf.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Wolf in White van cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.avidbookshop.com/book/9781250074713&quot;&gt;Wolf in White Van&lt;/a&gt; by John Darnielle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;march&quot;&gt;March&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/img/writing/2019-midyear/buxton.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Buxton Village Books Homepage&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;launched-buxton-village-books-at-buxtonvillagebookscom&quot;&gt;Launched Buxton Village Books at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.buxtonvillagebooks.com/&quot;&gt;buxtonvillagebooks.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gee Gee, owner of Buxton Village Books, runs a bookstore on Cape Hatteras — a beautiful island off the cost of North Carolina. Books…on the beach! I don’t think I’ve ever been more jealous of a client’s life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/img/writing/2019-midyear/allison.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;My portfolio site homepage&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;launched-my-portfolio-site&quot;&gt;Launched my portfolio site!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a BIG achievement of mine. I build and launch websites all the time for my clients, but launching something of my own was so much work.
My new portfolio site included an overall rebrand, eight new portfolio pieces and updated photography and copy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What I Read:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/img/writing/2019-midyear/marriage.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Marriage Plot book cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.avidbookshop.com/book/9780374203054&quot;&gt;The Marriage Plot&lt;/a&gt; by Jeffrey Eugenides&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/img/writing/2019-midyear/poisonwood.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Poisonwood Bible cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.avidbookshop.com/book/9780060786502&quot;&gt;The Poisonwood Bible&lt;/a&gt; by Barbara Kingslover&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;april&quot;&gt;April&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/img/portfolio/avid/avid.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Avid Bookshop gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;launched-site-redesign-for-avid-bookshop-at-avidbookshopcom&quot;&gt;Launched site redesign for Avid Bookshop at &lt;a href=&quot;https://avidbookshop.com&quot;&gt;avidbookshop.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I originally designed and developed the Avid Bookshop website back in 2016. In April 2019, we launched a site redesign that featured a clean, modern and cheerful design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What I Read:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/img/writing/2019-midyear/circe.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Circe book cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.avidbookshop.com/book/9780316556347&quot;&gt;Circe&lt;/a&gt; by Madeline Miller&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/img/writing/2019-midyear/woods.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;In The Woods cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.avidbookshop.com/book/9780143113492&quot;&gt;In the Woods&lt;/a&gt; by Tana French&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;may&quot;&gt;May&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/img/portfolio/LD/ld-slides.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Homepage of Lamar Dodd School of Art&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;launched-site-redesign-for-lamar-dodd-school-of-art-at-artugaedu&quot;&gt;Launched site redesign for Lamar Dodd School of Art at &lt;a href=&quot;https://art.uga.edu&quot;&gt;art.uga.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I originally designer and developed the Lamar Dodd School of Art in Feburary 2018. However, we needed to update the site to Drupal 8 and I took this opportunity to also introduce a fresh design. It’s beautiful — I love it!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What I Read:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/img/writing/2019-midyear/chernoybl.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Voices of Chernobyl cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.avidbookshop.com/book/9781628973303&quot;&gt;Voices of Chernobyl&lt;/a&gt; by Svetlana Alexievich&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;june&quot;&gt;June&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/img/writing/2019-midyear/daisy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Our sweet angel baby Daisy. Our loved pug.&quot; /&gt;
June began with a devastating loss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On June 1, Daisy, our sweet pug angel baby, passed. She became very sick and we needed to end her suffering. She went to sleep in Jeff and I’s arms. Her brother Cooper misses her very much.
It still hurts, I’m crying as I write this. We loved her SO much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/img/writing/2019-midyear/select-trees.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Homepage of Select Trees&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;launched-select-trees-at-selecttreescom&quot;&gt;Launched Select Trees at &lt;a href=&quot;https://selecttrees.com&quot;&gt;selecttrees.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Select Trees is a tree nursery that provides trees to landscape architects for large-scale projects. Their nursery, located in Crawford, Georgia, is an impressive production.
The website includes an interactive map of where their trees have been planted, multiple tier memberships and in-depth tree profiles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/img/writing/2019-midyear/tpg.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Homepage of The Pearl Girls&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;launched-the-pearl-girls-redeisgn-at-thepearlgirlscom&quot;&gt;Launched The Pearl Girls redeisgn at &lt;a href=&quot;https://thepearlgirls.com&quot;&gt;thepearlgirls.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year I launched The Pearl Girls sister site, &lt;a href=&quot;https://theworldofpearl.com&quot;&gt;The World of Pearl&lt;/a&gt; and this year I tackled the main Pearl Girls website.
The new design features a new mega menu, jewelry repair section, blog and overall more user-friendly modern design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What I Read:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/img/writing/2019-midyear/pachinko.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pachinko cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.avidbookshop.com/book/9781455563937&quot;&gt;Pachinko&lt;/a&gt; by Min Jin Lee&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/img/writing/2019-midyear/dreamers.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The dreamers cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.avidbookshop.com/book/9780812994162&quot;&gt;The Dreamers&lt;/a&gt; by Karen Thompson Walker&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;june-30-2019&quot;&gt;June 30, 2019&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;seven-sites-launched-10-books-read-one-trip-taken&quot;&gt;Seven sites launched, 10 books read, one trip taken.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point last year (2018) I had launched 10 sites already. But this year (2019) I’ve made more money. I’m getting smart about this business!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See you at Christmas with another review!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Allison Skinner</name></author><category term="2019" /><category term="Review" /><summary type="html">We’re already halfway through 2019, crazy right? I’m saying that’s “crazy” when really 2019 has been very…chill. And I like it. I like it a LOT.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/writing/2019-midyear/midyear-2019.gif" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How to File Your Taxes as a Freelancer</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/writing/How-File-Taxes-as-a-Freelancer" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to File Your Taxes as a Freelancer" /><published>2019-03-28T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-03-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/writing/How-File-Taxes-as-a-Freelancer</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/writing/How-File-Taxes-as-a-Freelancer">&lt;iframe height=&quot;431&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; margin-bottom:2em;&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; title=&quot;Floating 3D Cube HTML &amp;amp; CSS&quot; src=&quot;//codepen.io/adskinner/embed/LaKwGv/?height=431&amp;amp;theme-id=light&amp;amp;default-tab=result&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; allowtransparency=&quot;true&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot;&gt;
  See the Pen &lt;a href=&quot;https://codepen.io/adskinner/pen/LaKwGv/&quot;&gt;Floating 3D Cube HTML &amp;amp; CSS&lt;/a&gt; by Allison Skinner
  (&lt;a href=&quot;https://codepen.io/adskinner&quot;&gt;@adskinner&lt;/a&gt;) on &lt;a href=&quot;https://codepen.io&quot;&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I recently just filed my taxes for 2018. This will be my fourth year filing taxes post-college and also my fourth year filing taxes as “sole proprietor” (aka freelancer).
When filing and saving for taxes as a sole proprietor, it’s a little different than being a full-time employee of a company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It’s different because ZERO money is taken out for taxes when you are being paid as an independent contractor or freelancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;So when tax time comes around, you have to claim &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; the money you’ve made and then pay taxes on &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; that money you’ve made. This likely means you’ll owe thousands and thousands of dollars in taxes. If you don’t have that money already saved, taxes could be a huge hit to your finances and quality of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;With good, smart and militant habits, I’ve always had plenty of money saved for taxes and the money I owe has never been a shock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;put-away-30-of-every-single-check-you-get-into-an-escrow-account-i-mean-it-every-single-one&quot;&gt;Put away 30% of every single check you get into an escrow account. I mean it! Every. Single. One.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This can be hard to stomach. I know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember the first time I got paid as a freelancer was with a $1,500 check. I remember holding it in my hands and being like “ONE THOUSAND FIVE HUNDRED FREAKING DOLLARS!!!”
That’s a lot for someone a few months out of college.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My mom works at an investment/banking office down the street from me, so I skipped into her office to deposit my first BIG check.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She took the check, punched a few numbers into her calculator and said, “Good job, Allison! I’ll just take out $450 for taxes.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“WHAT!” I said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My mom then explained to me that this &lt;em&gt;big&lt;/em&gt; check was actually a lie. It wasn’t worth $1,500. It was worth $1,050. And that $450 would go into a separate account called an “escrow account” and it would sit there, untouched, until I paid my taxes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was pretty upset, and I had a new found comraderie with all the older people I heard grumbling about “taxes” my whole life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking back this is one of best lessons I learned about my finances and I was lucky that I learned it with my &lt;em&gt;first&lt;/em&gt; freelancing check.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot of freelancers/young professionals that think their $1,500 checks ARE $1,500 checks and they spend every single penny. Then they file their taxes and they owe thousands of dollars they don’t have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now every time I deposit a check, I take out 30% &lt;em&gt;immediately&lt;/em&gt;. I don’t even think about it! Once the money lands in my escrow account I don’t even consider it my own money anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;if-you-cant-afford-to-put-away-30-of-every-check-you-make-then-you-should-be-charging-more&quot;&gt;If you can’t afford to put away 30% of every check you make, then you should be charging more.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you start saving for taxes, you will never look at money the same way again! I look at all money with 30% taken out of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I’m putting together a quote, I’ll take the final amount and subtract 30%. Do I still like the amount? Am I still being fairly compensated with 30% taken out? Can I pay my bills and get groceries with 30% taken out?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If my answer is no, I raise the amount. It may &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt; like I’m overcharging my client, but every business – every person! – has to pay taxes! Like Benjamin Franklin said, “in this world nothing can be said to be certain, except death and taxes.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;get-a-cpa&quot;&gt;Get a CPA&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doing your taxes as a freelancer isn’t as easy for people that have one full-time job with one company. Freelancers typically have mulitple 1099s and lots of business deductions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we run the risk of paying &lt;em&gt;so much&lt;/em&gt; in taxes, having a good CPA is a worthy investment. A CPA will not only file your taxes for you, but will also give advice and counseling on how to run your business at a lower tax cost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;get-an-ein-employee-identifcation-number&quot;&gt;Get an EIN (Employee Identifcation Number)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An EIN can be used in place of your social security number on business tax forms (W-9s, 1099s). I like to keep my social security number private, so I provide my EIN for all my business-related tax forms. This can prevent identity theft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will also need an EIN if you wish to apply for a business loan or open business bank account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can apply for an EIN online &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.irs.gov/businesses/small-businesses-self-employed/apply-for-an-employer-identification-number-ein-online&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-does-the-irs-know-im-getting-paid&quot;&gt;How does the IRS know I’m getting paid?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s say you provide a professional service for a client (photography, logo design, something like that) and you get paid for it. The client you did work for will likely want to claim that cost as a business deduction on their taxes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your client paid you MORE than $600, they have to issue a 1099 to claim that tax deduction. In order to issue a 1099 they need to have your name, address and social security or employee identification number. A client will request this information from you with a W-9 form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the client has a signed W-9 from you, they will send you and the IRS a copy of a 1099.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That 1099 is evidence that you were paid X amount and you will owe taxes on that X amount.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-if-i-got-paid-less-than-600-for-my-professional-services&quot;&gt;What if I got paid LESS than $600 for my professional services&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you were paid &lt;em&gt;less&lt;/em&gt; than $600 for a professional service, the client that paid you won’t have to issue a 1099 to claim the cost as a business deduction. That means that there isn’t an official paper trail with the IRS that you were paid that amount. It may be tempting to not claim that payment you received because then you won’t have to pay taxes on it. However, if you were ever audited by the IRS and they found evidence of you being paid and not claiming it, then you will be in legal trouble. Not worth it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-if-i-dont-receive-1099s-for-everything-i-was-paid-in-the-past-year&quot;&gt;What if I don’t receive 1099s for everything I was paid in the past year?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s say you did get paid &lt;em&gt;over&lt;/em&gt; $600 for a number of projects, but you’ve only received &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; 1099s from your clients. It’s not your responsibility to make sure there’s a 1099 attached to every penny you’ve made in a year. If a client wants to claim you as a business expense, it’s their responsibility to issue a 1099. However, it is &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; responsibility to claim &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; of the money you’ve made in the past year, whether or not there are 1099s backing up everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re honest about what you’ve made, then there will be no trouble if you’re ever audited by the IRS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;know-what-you-can-deduct-on-your-taxes&quot;&gt;Know what you can deduct on your taxes.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are a freelancer that also means that you are a business owner. That means that you can make tax deductions for your business. This is a great opportunity to lower your tax costs. Instead of owing a full 30% of your income, with smart deductions, you could owe less!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following is a list of things I deduct from my taxes each year, but I also recommend speaking to your CPA about what deductions are possible for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;here-are-some-things-you-should-claim-as-deductions-on-your-taxes&quot;&gt;Here are some things you should claim as deductions on your taxes:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your rent or mortgage (if you work from home)&lt;/strong&gt;
If you work from home, even part-time, you should be getting a partial deduction on your rent or mortgage. You will need to know the square feet of your entire home and the square feet of your office. This will help determine what percentage of your rent/mortgage can be deducted.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your utilities (if you work from home)&lt;/strong&gt;
You need power, water and wifi to run your business! So deduct it!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your phone bill.&lt;/strong&gt;
Do you talk to clients on the phone? Well, then your phone is a business asset and your monthly phone bill should be part of your deductions.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your health insurance.&lt;/strong&gt;
As a business owner, you can 100% deduct your health insurance premium! This was the difference between me choosing poor and decent healthcare for myself.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Driving to and from your office and/or client meetings.&lt;/strong&gt;
For driving deductions, you will submit the mileage you’ve driven for business purposes.
You should keep a detailed log of each “business” drive with your destination and number of miles driven.
This can apply to IRL client meetings or drives to your office (if you have an office outside your home).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Any subscriptions/memberships that are business related.&lt;/strong&gt;
For me this is my Dropbox, Adobe Creative Cloud and GitHub Pro accounts. I claim these all as deductions.
As a developer, this can also include any premium plugins, hosting plans, domain names, etc. that I have purchased.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Office Equipment / Supplies&lt;/strong&gt;
This includes your laptop computer, desktop computer, desk, headphones, trackpad, keyboard, etc. Also small things like notebooks, pens, etc.
I bought a laptop and desktop computer my first year freelancing and it provided a sizable deduction in my taxes.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Any services that you subcontract&lt;/strong&gt;
Freelancers paying freelancers! I’ve subcontracted logo design, photography and copywriting for certain projects. I’ve also had a paid intern. If you’ve paid someone for a professional service over $600 and you’d like to claim it as a deduction on your taxes, you will need to for that independent professional to complete a W-9 form. If you are currently a freelancer, you’ve likely filled out a W-9 form before. Once you have a W-9 from the professional, you can file and send a 1099.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;have-receiptsdocumentation-for-all-of-your-business-deductions&quot;&gt;Have receipts/documentation for &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; of your business deductions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you file your taxes and claim your deductions, the IRS will not require receipt or documentation of the purchases you’ve claimed. &lt;em&gt;However&lt;/em&gt;, you should have receipt/documentation for everything in case you are audited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to keep track of paper receipts, so I try to have an email receipt record of everything I pay for. It can also be helpful to have a separate business-only credit card. That way you have a full record of business costs on &lt;em&gt;one&lt;/em&gt; card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pay-quarterly-taxes&quot;&gt;Pay Quarterly Taxes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of paying &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; your taxes by the end of the fiscal year (April), you can opt to pay your taxes quarterly. Your CPA will set-up an estimated amount for your quarterly taxes. This is based on your past income.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suggest paying quarterly taxes as a freelancer because it allows you to pay your taxes throughout the year instead of paying a huge sum at the end of the year. Since none of my income is taxed initially, my escrow account will get to be a sizable amount pretty quickly. Instead of having that money sit in my account “burning a hole in my pocket”, I want to flush it out quarterly with tax payments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quarterly tax amounts are based on an &lt;em&gt;estimate&lt;/em&gt; of what your taxes will be for the year. So that means once you file your taxes, your CPA will review if you owe any extra money for taxes or if you are eligible for a tax return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on my experiences, if you have a lot of money left in your escrow after paying all of your quarterly taxes, you’ll likely owe a good bit for taxes. Honestly, that’s something you should be proud of! You had a successful year. But if your escrow account is fairly depleted, you are more likely to break even or possibly get a tax return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;keep-learning-each-year&quot;&gt;Keep learning each year&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each year I have the goal of becoming smarter about my taxes and learning something new that could save me money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year, I’m filing my first 1099s for work I’ve contracted out. So, I’ve learned about how to get those costs claimed and deducted. I also learned that my health insurance is deductible!
CPAs are available year round for you to “bend their ear” about possible deductions, changes in tax law and how to properly classify your business.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Allison Skinner</name></author><category term="taxes" /><summary type="html">See the Pen Floating 3D Cube HTML &amp;amp; CSS by Allison Skinner (@adskinner) on CodePen.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/writing/19-03-28/taxes.gif" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Is Jekyll the right platform for your website?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/writing/is-jekyll-the-right-platform-for-your-website" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Is Jekyll the right platform for your website?" /><published>2019-03-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-03-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/writing/is-jekyll-the-right-platform-for-your-website</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/writing/is-jekyll-the-right-platform-for-your-website">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Let’s start by learning some basics…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-jekyll&quot;&gt;What is Jekyll?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; is a static site generator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-a-static-site-generator&quot;&gt;What is a static site generator?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A static site generator compiles your text, css and javascript files and spits out a templated website of static HTML files &lt;em&gt;without&lt;/em&gt; a database. A CMS, like Wordpress, holds your content in a database and the server will query the database(s) to generate HTML files for your website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to continue reading about what static site generators are, I think David Walsh provides a great explanation in his article, “&lt;a href=&quot;https://davidwalsh.name/introduction-static-site-generators&quot;&gt;An Introduction to Static Site Generators&lt;/a&gt;”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David Walsh says static site generators “can be for everyone, just not for everything”. Anyone can setup and manage a Jekyll website, but is a Jekyll website the right fit for their business? I’m going to try to answer that for you today!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;jekyll-is-not-the-right-fit-for-you-if&quot;&gt;Jekyll IS NOT the right fit for you if…&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-you-want-real-time-content-on-your-website&quot;&gt;1. You want real-time content on your website.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Examples of real-time content is a “popular posts” block that lists the most viewed articles today, a “recommended articles” block based on what you’ve been reading. This real-time content is possible through a database.
If this type of content is important to you, then Jekyll is likely not the best fit for your business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-you-want-to-run-an-online-store&quot;&gt;2. You want to run an online store.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Running an online store requires a database for multiple reasons – customer profiles, customer orders, products, coupons, etc. Also you need to be able to link third-party payment methods like Square, Paypal, Stripe, etc. to your website. If you want to run an online shop, I’d recommend Wordpress or Shopify.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would like to add that if you only want to sell a few items or you are simply trying to raise donations, Jekyll could still be an appropriate fit for you. You can embed paypal buttons to your website. For example, &lt;a href=&quot;https://moz.com/blog/kyle-rush-reveals-how-the-obama-campaign-broke-every-online-fundraising-record-free-mozcon-video&quot;&gt;Barack Obama raised $250 million of donations through his Jekyll 2012 campaign website&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-you-want-a-ui-user-interface-to-be-able-to-manageupdate-your-website&quot;&gt;3. You want a UI (user interface) to be able to manage/update your website.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having a UI is important for website managers that have limited technical experience. A UI allows you to have dashboard with clear buttons that say “add new post” or “add new page”. A UI allows you to have a content editor to format text. A UI allows you to push your changes by clicking the “publish now” button.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When working with Jekyll, you won’t have a UI. To add a new post, you won’t be clicking any clearly labelled buttons. Instead, you will add a markdown file to your “posts” folder and then push your changes to your live repo. This could be a little overwhelming to some, but I think these skills that can be quickly learned!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;jekyll-is-the-right-fit-for-you-if&quot;&gt;Jekyll IS the right fit for you if…&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-your-website-is-relatively-simple&quot;&gt;1. Your website is relatively simple&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would say your website is relatively simple if your site only needs a few informational pages (“about” page for example), a blog and a contact page with a contact form. That’s essentially how simple my website is! If you don’t need real-time content, a robust online store or user-generated content…then yes, Jekyll could be a great option for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-you-want-your-website-to-run-fast&quot;&gt;2. You want your website to run FAST&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Static site generators, like Jekyll, typically load 10x faster than a CMS website. My most image-heavy pages load in under 1.2 seconds. That is unbeatable speed compared to Wordpress or Squarespace site loads. This could be especially beneficial to websites that have many large, high-resolution images.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-you-want-a-secure-website&quot;&gt;3. You want a secure website&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most hackers use database exploits to hack your website. Without a database, the possibility for hacking is greatly reduced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-you-want-version-control-for-your-entire-website-content-and-code&quot;&gt;4. You want version control for your entire website (content and code)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Jekyll, you can manage your entire site from a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/&quot;&gt;git repository&lt;/a&gt;. (You can also host it for free with &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;Github Pages&lt;/a&gt;!) This is a developer standard for most projects, but usually the actual content (posts, pages, images) sits in a database that’s completely separate from your repository. On a jekyll site, &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; your content will be in your git repo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ok-i-want-a-jekyll-website-for-my-business-now-what&quot;&gt;Ok I want a Jekyll website for my business, now what?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Awesome!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to get started on your own, visit Jekyll’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; and get started with their documentation. I’d also recommend &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=T1itpPvFWHI&amp;amp;list=PLLAZ4kZ9dFpOPV5C5Ay0pHaa0RJFhcmcB&quot;&gt;Mike Dane’s youtube series&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like help with website design, Jekyll installation or Jekyll training – please get in &lt;a href=&quot;/contact&quot;&gt;touch&lt;/a&gt;! I’d love to help.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Allison Skinner</name></author><category term="Jekyll" /><category term="Static Sites" /><summary type="html">Let’s start by learning some basics…</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why I chose to build a portfolio site with Jekyll and host it on Github Pages</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/writing/Why-I-chose-to-build-my-portfolio-site-on-jekyll" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why I chose to build a portfolio site with Jekyll and host it on Github Pages" /><published>2019-03-22T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-03-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/writing/Why-I-chose-to-build-my-portfolio-site-on-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/writing/Why-I-chose-to-build-my-portfolio-site-on-jekyll">&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-why-didnt-i-build-my-website-in-wordpress-or-drupal-because-thats-what-i-build-most-of-my-client-websites-with&quot;&gt;1. Why didn’t I build my website in Wordpress or Drupal? (Because that’s what I build most of my client websites with)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For my clients, I primarily build websites on &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.org/&quot;&gt;Wordpress&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://drupal.org&quot;&gt;Drupal&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://shopify.com&quot;&gt;Shopify&lt;/a&gt;. I love working on these platforms because it gives my clients with limited technical expertise the ability to update and manage their own websites.
However, I do have the technical experience to update/edit my personal website without any admin interface or user dashboard. I wanted a lean publishing platform that would allow for me push changes and manage a blog with ease – that’s why I chose Jekyll!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-why-jekyll-whats-so-great-about-it&quot;&gt;2. Why Jekyll? What’s so great about it.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; is a static site generator. A static site has no database, it’s really just turning simple markup (text, images, etc.) into a web page. You install Jekyll into a Git repo, add some files, push the changes and &lt;em&gt;voila&lt;/em&gt; there’s your website. The lack of a database is impossible for some businesses (online shops) but can be beneficial for others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;jekyll-has-a-variety-of-benefits&quot;&gt;Jekyll has a variety of benefits…&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They load super fast.&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A database-less static website usually loads 10x faster than a website with a CMS. Wow!&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;For example, even the most image-heavy pages of my website load in under 1.2 seconds. That’s a speed a Wordpress site could only dream of!&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They are very secure&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Since a Jekyll website is only serving static files there are no scripting or database security exploits possible for hackers.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEO benefits&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Wordpress and other CMS have a lot of SEO tools, but they don’t have this level of site speed on their side. And Google loves fast websites! Also, it’s easier to maintain a clean file path structure in Jekyll (in my opinion) and Google loves clean file path structures.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Built-in blogging platform.&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Jekyll has blogging functionality out of the box.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Adding a blog post is as simple as adding a markdown file to your posts folder. There is no content editor or admin dashboard to deal with!&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Has SASS compiler pre-installed.&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;SASS can be fairly straightforward to write, but setting up a server-compatible compiler is sometimes not that easy. Luckily, Jekyll has your SASS compiler already set up for you.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You can serve website on local computer&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If you want to view your Jekyll site before publishing to the production, all you have to do is run “jekyll serve” from your terminal. It will run your SASS compiler and all the other Jekyll magic and serve your website on your local IP.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Built with liquid&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Liquid is PHP’s more attractive cousin and it’s a lot of fun to code in.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Layouts” and “Includes” allow for fast building&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If you are building a raw HTML site and you need to add a new page, you’ll have to copy over the head, header, main menu, footer, etc. It’s a tedious process and makes changes/updates to your code difficult to manage.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Jekyll has support for ‘layouts’ and ‘includes’. ‘Layouts’ allow you to create a structure for different page templates, such as ‘posts’ or ‘portfolio examples’.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;“Includes” are like blocks, they are snippets of HTML that you can &lt;em&gt;include&lt;/em&gt; anywhere on your site. If you ever update your “layout” or an “include”, it’ll update sitewide.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-why-host-on-github-pages&quot;&gt;3. Why host on &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;Github Pages&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The simplest answer is that it’s FREE.&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Most hosting plans start at least at $10/month, but decent hosting plans are usually $35/month or higher. So with Github pages, I’m saving hundreds of dollars a year. (GH Pages is only compatible with static sites, so this isn’t free hosting for all!)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The SSL certificate is free &amp;amp; pre-installed.&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;All Github Pages hosted websites have a free, automatic SSL certificate.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You can manage your website directly from your git repo.&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Once you push your changes to your gh-pages branch, it’s pushed to your production site. Easy as that!&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would a Jekyll website be a good fit for your business? Read my post that breaks down the pros and cons of Jekyll websites [COMING SOON].&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Allison Skinner</name></author><category term="Jekyll" /><category term="Portfolio Website" /><category term="Static Sites" /><category term="Github Pages" /><summary type="html">1. Why didn’t I build my website in Wordpress or Drupal? (Because that’s what I build most of my client websites with) For my clients, I primarily build websites on Wordpress, Drupal or Shopify. I love working on these platforms because it gives my clients with limited technical expertise the ability to update and manage their own websites. However, I do have the technical experience to update/edit my personal website without any admin interface or user dashboard. I wanted a lean publishing platform that would allow for me push changes and manage a blog with ease – that’s why I chose Jekyll!</summary></entry></feed>